うむ
Urutori, you will tell me, won't you?
ウルトリィ
聞かせてくれるな
High Priest!
オルヤンクル
Yes...
はい
The one who has been dormant in Camus
is the first person, our ancestor.
カミュの中に眠っていた彼女こそ
最初の人にして わたくしたちの始祖様です
The spirit of our ancestor reincarnates in the
bodies of our people throughout time.
始祖様の魂は わたくしたち
オンカミヤリューの体を憑代とし 現臨なされます
For what reason?
何のために
According to legend, it is so that
she can be with Witsalnemitea.
伝承によれば
ウィツァルネミテアと共にあるために
Are you saying that that man
is Witsalnemitea?
あの男が そうだというのか
He said that I was another
manifestation of himself.
あいつは私を もう１人の自分だと言った
My strength... I thought...
こっちから 私もまた
Camus...
カミュは禁じられた地
オンカミヤムカイの宗廟にいるはずです
should be in the mausoleum in the forbidden
region of Onkamiyamukai.
I prayed that this day would not come.
この日が来なければよいと
祈っていました
How wonderful if only it could
have been avoided!
避けられるものなら
どれほど良かったでしょうか
Please, please save Camus' soul.
どうか どうか
カミュの魂をお救いください
Camus...
カミュ
My Camus...
わたくしのカミュ
kodomo no goro no yume wa
The dream I had when I was a child,
子供の頃の夢は　色褪せない落書きで
iroase nai rakugaki de
were drawn to my heart's desire
omou mama kaki suberasete
with scribbles that wouldn't fade away
思うまま書き滑らせて
描く未来へとつながる
egaku mirai he to tsunagaru
and are connected to the future i draw.
Utawarerumono
sumiwataru sora
The clear skies
澄み渡る空　果てしないほど青く
hateshinai hodo aoku
were endlessly blue.
mujaki na kokoro ni
And my innocent heart,
無邪気な心に　充たされ魅かれてく
mitasare hikareteku
being satisfied, was attracted to them.
yagate jiyuu ni tobimawareru
I finally obtained wings
やがて自由に飛びまわれる
翼(はね)を手に入れて
hane wo teni irete
with which I could fly freely.
muku na hitomi wa motometeku
I want to go to the end of the skies
無垢な瞳は求めてく
空の向こうへ　行きたいな
sora no mukou he ikitai na
which my pure eyes desire.
kore tonai negai kara
If one wish could be granted
止め処ない願いから　一つだけ叶うのなら
hitotsu dake kanau no nara
out of countless others...
dare ni mo yuzuri taku wa nai
I feel that it should be to grab onto a dream
誰にも譲りたくはない
夢を掴みたいと思うよ
yume wo tsukamitai to omou yo
and never be tempted to let go.
kodomo no goro no yume wa
The dreams I had when I was a child,
子供の頃の夢は　色褪せない落書きで
iroase nai rakugaki de
were drawn eternally,
itsuwademo kaki tsuzukerareta
with scribbles that wouldn't fade away
いつまでも描き続けられた
願う未来へとつながる
negau mirai he to tsunagaru
and are connected to the future I wish for.
Traces of an Ancient Dream
ふんっ
えいっ
You've improved.
腕を上げましたね
どうした もう勝てる気がしないか
What's the matter? You think you
can't beat me anymore?
実戦では手加減しません
I wouldn't hold back in actual combat.
ハハハハ　悪くねえってことだよ
He means you're not bad.
ふん
I still have much to master.
I cannot be satisfied with where I am.
まだまだだ　この程度でいいはずがない
ふん
しかし あまり直情的過ぎても
足元をすくわれるぞ
But if you're too impulsive, your opponent
will take advantage of it.
Brother, were you watching?
兄者　見ていたのか
Oboro...
オボロ
When I am gone, I want you to lead everyone.
私がいなくなったら
お前が皆を導いてやってくれ
Huh? What are you saying?
はあ？　何を言い出すんだ
I said I'd go anywhere with you, didn't I?
どこまでも兄者についていくと
言っただろう
How can you even say that?
そんなこと…
Hakuoro-san...
ハクオロさーん
クーヤさんが クーヤさんが
目を覚ましました
Kuuya-san...
Kuuya-san has come to!
フウ ウフフフッ ウフフフッ
ウーウ　ウフ ウフフフ…
アー アー　ウフッ ウフフフ…
ウウ ウー アーウー アーアー
Why?
なぜ？
I think Kuuya-sama has regressed to her childhood.
クーヤ様はきっと
子どもの頃に帰ったんです
To that period when she had no worries,
when she was happiest.
つらいことを忘れて 何の不安も無い
一番幸せだった頃に
Hakuoro...
I am here.
フウー
ここにいる
うっ クーヤ様は
ハクオロ様のことだけは覚えてて
Her Majesty remembers only Hakuoro-sama.
うーん　いや あー あーん
Forgive me...
すまない…
Forgive me!
すまない
皆を導け か
Lead everyone, huh?
Where are you planning to go, Brother?
兄者 どこへ行こうとしている
ハクオロ様
Hakuoro-sama...
Is he going somewhere?
どこかへ行かれるのですか
You're awake?
起きていたのか
はい
Yes...
具合はどうだ
How are you feeling?
久しぶりに いい気分です
I haven't felt so good in a while.
I see.
そうか
お兄様？
Brother?
ああ 兄者が 俺に
おかしなことを言うものでな
Oh well, Brother said something
strange to me, you see.
That's because you are his good friend.
お兄様が仲良しだから
アッハハハ　兄者と俺は兄弟だ
We are brothers!
Saying we're just "friends"
isn't quite the same.
仲良しというのは少し違うな
I don't understand.
ユズハには分かりません
Do you mean that Aru-chan and
Camus-chan are my sisters?
それじゃあ アルちゃんやカミュちゃんは
ユズハの姉妹なのですか
アッハハハ　そうだな
I guess. If you think so, then you are all sisters.
ユズハがそう思うなら皆姉妹だ
ウフフ
You're drinking quite a bit tonight.
今日は飲みますわね
I'm drinking for Genjimaru and the others too.
皆と ゲンジマル殿の分だ
Genjimaru...
ゲンジマル殿ね
I hear he died magnificently
for his sovereign.
主君のための立派な最期だったと聞く
I would like to have as brilliant an end.
某も そのように立派に散りたい
That's what happens when you keep
drinking and you can't handle it.
強くもないのに頑張るからですわ
But you really should show this cuter
side of you now and then.
でも たまにはこういう可愛いところも
見せてくれませんとね
聖上は 某がお守りいたしまする
Sire, I shall protect you...
Tuskuru-san...
トゥスクルさん
ヤマユラの里から始まった自分の旅も
どうやら終わりのようです
My journey that began in the village of Yamayura
appears to be at an end.
クーウ
Aruruu!
アルルゥ
ホアー
What's the matter?
どうしたんだ
Father, are you going to bring Camus-cchi back?
お父さん カミュちー迎えに行く？
Y... Yeah...
I'll go too.
アルルゥも行く
心配しないで
アルルゥは待っているといい
Do not worry about it. You wait here.
Father, you're not coming home.
お父さん 帰って来ない
あっは どうしてそう思うんだい
Why do you think that?
大丈夫　私はアルルゥと
ずっと一緒にいるよ
Do not worry, I will always be with you, Aruruu.
Eruruu?
エルルゥ
ハクオロさん　私もついて行きます
Hakuoro-san, I will go with you.
But I cannot get you two involved
in what is about to happen.
しかし これからのことで君たちを
巻き込むわけにはいかない
What are you saying?
何を言ってるんですか
Now, Aruruu, you can't come with us.
アルルゥも
あなたはついてきちゃ駄目でしょう
No!
嫌
グォーウ
If Mukkuru and I aren't there,
Father will be in danger.
アルルゥたちいないと お父さん危ない
Aruruu...
アルルゥ
Sire?
聖上
Where do you think you are going
without any guards?
護衛も無しに どちらへ
行かれるおつもりですか
Onkamiyamukai is a long way from here.
オンカミヤムカイまでは遠いですぜ
It is our duty to protect our king.
往路をお守りするのが 我らの務めです
Everyone...
皆さん
Brother!
兄者
Oboro...
オボロ
Then, I shall be on my way.
では 行ってまいります
姫様 私もお供に
Princess, I shall accompany you.
Munto, please remain here as envoy.
ムントは使者として
ここに残ってください
But Princess...
あ いや姫様あ
It is the wish of the High Priest.
オルヤンクルのご意志だ
あ あは…
Of course...
Urutori, it will be a difficult job,
but I will leave Camus to you.
ウルトリィ つらい役目だが カミュを頼む
Yes.
はい
So, this is the land of Onkamiyamukai.
ここが オンカミヤムカイ
There is a sealed gate up ahead.
この先に 封印の門があります
ル ビアン バス ギル ブー ビー
イェジ グ ネク チェル ジル アーン
It smells!
臭い
悪趣味ですわね
How disgusting...
カミュちー
Camus-cchi!
カミュ
Camus!
はっ カミュ
Camus...
We have come for you. Now, let's go home!
迎えに来た　さあ 帰ろう
No...
違う
私はムツミ　あなたたちを
通すわけにはいかないの
I am Mutsumi.
I cannot allow you through.
とおっ
Camus!
カミュ
Give Camus-cchi back!
カミュちー返せ
ガオー
Give her back!
返せ
カミュ
Camus!
That is my shadow, one of the many
personalities that exist within me.
あれは私の影
私の中に存在する 幾多の人格の１つ
If you had not come here, you could
have avoided learning this.
来なければ
何も知らないまま過ごせたのに
I came here to find out.
私は 知るためにここへ来た
Camus!
カミュ
Hakuoro-san!
ハクオロさん
Father!
お父さん
ええいっ
A dead end?
行き止まり
えっ う 何なの
What's going on?
I...
私は ここを
This place...
I know it!
知っている
Iceman...
アイスマン
It was just determined in the meeting
that you will be refrozen.
先ほどの議会で 君の再凍結が決定した
What do you mean?
何だ それは
It was decided that some time would be needed
before further research can be done on you.
これ以上の研究は
まだ時間がかかると判断された
You will be preserved as a valuable sample.
君は貴重なサンプルとして保存される
You mean I was brought back to life from my
frozen state just to be a research subject?
氷に閉じ込められていた自分を蘇生させたのは
研究材料のためだったというのか
I won't deny it. If you want to hate
me for it, feel free to do so.
否定はしない
恨みたければ存分に恨んでくれ
I will turn off the security system in here.
これから ここのセキュリティーを
無効化する
You can escape while it's off.
その間に逃げればいい
Why? If you do that, you will...
なぜ　そんなことをすれば あなたが
I am tired of this.
疲れたのだよ もう
Do you have any idea how heavily the act of
creating life weighs upon one's conscience?
生命を創造するということが
どれだけの罪の意識に苛まれるか 分かるかね
Is this your attempt to atone for your sins?
罪滅ぼしのつもりか
By and by, you become numb
to the sense of guilt,
罪の意識が麻痺してゆき
そしていつしか 何も感じなく
and eventually, you don't feel anything.
That is what I fear most!
それがたまらなく怖いのだ
Won't you escape with me?
一緒に逃げないのか
ハハハハ…　私はただの人間だ
I am an ordinary human being.
地上の環境には耐えられない
I cannot survive the environment
above ground.
I am a weakling, a foolish creature.
どうしようもなく ひ弱で
愚かな生き物なのだよ
アイスマン １つだけ頼みを
聞いてもらえないか
Iceman, will you do just one thing for me?
Mikoto...
ミコト
This girl has grown very fond of you.
その子は君によく懐いている
She will probably not be able to bear
the loneliness after you're gone.
君がいなくなったとき
その孤独に耐えられまい
ハハ お別れだ
It's time to say goodbye.
3510号　これからは自分のために
好きなように生きるといい
Number 3510, from now on live for
yourself, however you want.
Mikoto... He gave her a nice name.
ミコトか　良い名を付けてもらったな
And the Iceman...
A man who is not really a man.
アイスマン
人でありながら 人でない存在
This is as it should be.
これでいい
This is something man must
never attempt to control.
あれは決して
人が触れてはならないものだ
Playing god, toying with the brains
and organs of living beings,
神の真似をし 生命の脳や臓器を
もてあそぶことなど 人の身に余りに大それたこと
doing the unspeakable to human bodies...
I trifled far too much with the
lives of his children.
私は 彼の子らの命をもてあそび過ぎた
Father...
お父様
くはっ
What was that!?
今のは
Eruruu!
エルルゥ
Sister!
お姉ちゃん
Are you all right?
大丈夫か
はい
Yes...
I cannot allow you to approach Father's side.
お父様の元へは行かせない
Eruruu! Aruruu!
エルルゥ アルルゥ
Stop this, Camus!
やめるんだ カミュ
I have no intention of fighting you.
お前と戦うつもりは無い
うわっ ぐはっ
Camus, snap out of it!
カミュ 目を覚ますんだ
Camus!
カミュ！
Camus-cchi, no!
カミュちー 駄目
A... Aruruu...
アルルゥ？
カミュちー 一緒に帰る
Camus-cchi, let's go home together!
A... Aru-chan...
アル…ちゃん？ ううっ ううっ
があっ ぐうっ
Camus, let's go home!
Everyone is worried about you.
カミュ 戻ろう
皆心配している
Camus-chan!
カミュちゃん
That's enough.
そこまでだ
Father...
お父様
Why do you continue to do such things?
なぜ こんな真似を続ける
This is all for the love of my children.
全て 我が子らを愛するがために
Pulling strings from the shadows to cause
strife is for the sake of your children?
背後で糸を引き
争わせるのが子らのためか
Correct.
そうだ
By allowing them to fight for
the existence of their kind,
種の存亡をめぐっての争いともなれば
その種をさらなる高みへ昇華させる
I allow them to further elevate their kind.
Thus, I have watched over the
growth of my children,
私はそうして子らの成長を見守り 時に
少し手を差し伸べているに過ぎぬ
giving them a helping hand from
time to time. That is all.
What of those who lose?
負けた種はどうなる
You would leave them to their fate?
弱き者たちを見殺しにするのか
The losers are weeded out.
It is as simple as that.
敗れし者は淘汰される　それだけのこと
And what about that do you call "love"!?
それのどこが愛だ
What about you then?
ならば 汝はどうだ
Why did you teach your children how
to battle and then lead them?
なぜ子らにさまざまな技を教え 導いた？
How much death have you wrought,
using defense as an excuse?
守るためという詭弁で
どれだけの種を蹂躙した？
What is so different between what I am
doing and what you are doing?
私のしていることと
汝のしていること 何が違う
Enough!
黙れ
We both find great pleasure in granting
the wishes of our children.
我らは 愛し子の望みを
かなえることを至上の喜びとする
But in return, they must pay with
something of equal value.
だが 代わりにそれと同等の代償を
払ってもらわねばならない
What did you do in order to
save that child there?
汝は そこの娘の命を救うために
何をした？
So, that was...
やはりあれは
Did you not enter into a pact with that
girl in order to grant her wish?
その娘の願いをかなえるために
契約をしたのではないのか
Please stop this!
もうやめてください！
Please, stop...
もう やめてください
I... I am here of my own free will!
私は 私の意思でここにいます
Eruruu!
エルルゥ
That is all I have to say.
Be gone from my sight.
話はここまでだ
我が前から消え失せよ
何？
What?
In truth, we were not to meet again
until we go back into our sleep.
本来なら 再び眠りにつくまで
我らが出会ってはならない
The reason you both hate each other
and cannot come to terms
同じ存在だからこそ
分かり合えず憎しみ合う
is because you share a single soul.
今この瞬間にも 汝と戦う衝動に
駆られはするが
Even at this very moment, I am filled
with an urge to fight you,
だが 我が眷属 クンネカムンが敗れ
最後の駒も失った
but my people of Kunekamun have been defeated,
and I have lost my last chess piece.
This time, I have lost.
今回は私の負けだ
Do as you will with this world
until it is your time to sleep.
汝の眠りの時まで
この世を好きにするがよい
What's the matter, you empty shell of a man?
どうした 空蝉よ
Hakuoro-san...
ハクオロさん？
Eruruu, I am truly grateful to you.
エルルゥ 君には本当に感謝している
The two of you... Thank you for
all you have done for me!
２人とも 今までありがとう
Why?
どうして？　どうして
そんなこと言うんですか
Why do you say that?
ハクオロ… さん？
Hakuoro-san?
Eruruu, I hereby nullify your pact with me.
エルルゥ 今ここに 汝との契約を破棄する
Now you are free.
これでお前は自由だ
-ハクオロさん
-お父さん
Hakuoro-san!
Father!
来るな！
Stay back!
I have not told you my real name yet, have I?
まだ言ってなかったな
私の本当の名を
Don't...
駄目…
My name...
私の…
No...
駄目
My name is...
名は
No!
駄目ー！
I will cut us free from this fate,
right here and now!
今ここで この定めを絶ち切る
Will you now?
そうか
But it is said that no human can defeat us.
だが 何人たりとも我らを
滅ぼすことはできぬというのに
Father...
お父様
Father?
お父さん
Hakuoro-san...
ハクオロさん
Hakuoro-san!
ハクオロさーん！
ぎゃおー
What's going on?
どういうことだ
I think it would be wise for us
to retreat as well.
わたくしたちも 退散した方が
よろしいですわね
What are those?
何だ あれは
Monsters?
化け物？
Hakuoro-sama...
ハクオロ様
What!?
何だと
あれが兄者だっていうのか
Do you mean that's Brother!?
The great god, Witsalnemitea...
大神ウィツァルネミテア
Brother!
兄者ー！
炎さえも凍てついた
honou sae mo itetsuita
I seek the solitude
kokuno naka moto mu
that freezes even flames.
孤独の中求む
tamashi kara musubitsuki
Connecting with your soul,
魂から結びつき 私を恋い温めて
watashi wo koi atatamete
warm me with your love.
嗚呼　祈りの言葉がふるえ
a inori no kotoba ga furue
Ah...the words of prayer tremble...
a yowaki no chika kiete mo
Ah even if the faint-hearted
were to disappear...
嗚呼　弱きいのちが消えても
kurikaesu innen no nagare tadori
Following the recurring paths of fate.
くりかえす　輪廻の流れ辿り
owaranai sekai no shukumei wo mitsumeteru
I gaze upon the never-ending world's destiny.
終わらない世界の宿命を見つめてる
くりかえし　詠われる者達よ
kurikaeshi utawareru mono tachi yo
Oh the ones being sung continuously
守られてまどろむ宵
mamorarete madoromu you ni
be protected and sleep.
Him Whose Song is Sung